For the last 50 years.
[AI] 在过去的50年里。
a lot of smart. well-resourced people -- some of you. no doubt --
[AI] 非常聪明。资源丰富的人——你们中的一些人。毫无疑问--
have been trying to figure out how to reduce poverty
[AI] 我一直在努力想办法减少贫困
in the United States.
[AI] 在美国。
People have created and invested millions of dollars
[AI] 人们创造并投资了数百万美元
into non-profit organizations with the mission of helping people who are poor.
[AI] 进入以帮助穷人为使命的非营利组织。
They've created think tanks
[AI] 他们建立了智囊团
that study issues like education. job creation and asset-building.
[AI] 研究教育等问题。创造就业和资产建设。
and then advocated for policies to support our most marginalized communities.
[AI] 然后倡导支持我们最边缘化社区的政策。
They've written books and columns and given passionate speeches.
[AI] 他们写过书，写过专栏，发表过热情的演讲。
decrying the wealth gap that is leaving more and more people
[AI] 谴责日益扩大的贫富差距
entrenched at the bottom end of the income scale.
[AI] 在收入表的底部根深蒂固。
And that effort has helped.
[AI] 这一努力起到了帮助作用。
But it's not enough.
[AI] 但这还不够。
Our poverty rates haven't changed that much in the last 50 years.
[AI] 在过去50年中，我们的贫困率变化不大。
since the War on Poverty was launched.
[AI] 自从反贫困战争开始以来。
I'm here to tell you
[AI] 我是来告诉你的
that we have overlooked the most powerful and practical resource.
[AI] 我们忽略了最强大和最实用的资源。
Here it is:
[AI] 这是：
people who are poor.
[AI] 穷人。
Up in the left-hand corner is Jobana. Sintia and Bertha.
[AI] 左上角是乔巴纳。辛提亚和伯莎。
They met when they all had small children.
[AI] 他们都有小孩时认识的。
through a parenting class at a family resource center
[AI] 通过家庭资源中心的育儿课程
in San Francisco.
[AI] 在旧金山。
As they grew together as parents and friends.
[AI] 他们作为父母和朋友一起成长。
they talked a lot about how hard it was to make money when your kids are little.
[AI] 他们谈论了很多当你的孩子还小的时候赚钱是多么的困难。
Child care is expensive.
[AI] 托儿费用很高。
more than they'd earn in a job.
[AI] 比他们在工作中赚的还多。
Their husbands worked.
[AI] 他们的丈夫工作。
but they wanted to contribute financially. too.
[AI] 但他们想在经济上做出贡献。也
So they hatched a plan.
[AI] 所以他们想出了一个计划。
They started a cleaning business.
[AI] 他们开始做清洁生意。
They plastered neighborhoods with flyers
[AI] 他们在社区张贴传单
and handed business cards out to their families and friends.
[AI] 并将名片分发给家人和朋友。
and soon. they had clients calling.
[AI] 很快。他们有客户打电话来。
Two of them would clean the office or house
[AI] 他们中的两个会打扫办公室或房子
and one of them would watch the kids.
[AI] 其中一个会看着孩子们。
They'd rotate who'd cleaned and who'd watch the kids.
[AI] 他们会轮换谁打扫，谁照看孩子。
(Laughs) It's awesome. right?
[AI] （笑）太棒了。正当
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
And they split the money three ways.
[AI] 他们把钱分成三份。
It was not a full-time gig.
[AI] 这不是一场全职演出。
no one could watch the little ones all day.
[AI] 没有人能整天看着这些小家伙。
But it made a difference for their families.
[AI] 但这对他们的家庭产生了影响。
Extra money to pay for bills when a husband's work hours were cut.
[AI] 当丈夫的工作时间被削减时，额外的钱用来支付账单。
Money to buy the kids clothes as they were growing.
[AI] 孩子们长大后买衣服的钱。
A little extra money in their pockets
[AI] 他们口袋里有点多余的钱
to make them feel some independence.
[AI] 让他们感到有些独立。
Up in the top-right corner is Theresa and her daughter. Brianna.
[AI] 右上角是特里萨和她的女儿。布丽安娜。
Brianna is one of those kids
[AI] 布丽安娜就是这些孩子中的一个
with this sparkly. infectious. outgoing personality.
[AI] 用这个闪闪发光的。传染性的外向的性格。
For example. when Rosie.
[AI] 例如当罗西。
a little girl who spoke only Spanish. moved in next door.
[AI] 一个只会说西班牙语的小女孩。搬到隔壁去了。
Brianna. who spoke only English.
[AI] 布莱安娜。他只会说英语。
borrowed her mother's tablet and found a translation app
[AI] 借了她母亲的平板电脑，找到了一个翻译应用程序
so the two of them could communicate.
[AI] 这样他们两个就可以交流了。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
I know. right?
[AI] 我知道。正当
Rosie's family credits Brianna with helping Rosie to learn English.
[AI] 罗西的家人感谢布里安娜帮助罗西学习英语。
A few years ago.
[AI] 几年前。
Brianna started to struggle academically.
[AI] 布丽安娜开始在学业上挣扎。
She was growing frustrated and kind of withdrawn
[AI] 她越来越沮丧，有点孤僻
and acting out in class.
[AI] 在课堂上表演。
And her mother was heartbroken over what was happening.
[AI] 她母亲对所发生的一切感到心碎。
Then they found out that she was going to have to repeat second grade
[AI] 然后他们发现她不得不重读二年级
and Brianna was devastated.
[AI] 布丽安娜被摧毁了。
Her mother felt hopeless and overwhelmed and alone
[AI] 她母亲感到绝望、不知所措和孤独
because she knew that her daughter was not getting the support she needed.
[AI] 因为她知道她的女儿没有得到她需要的支持。
and she did not know how to help her.
[AI] 她不知道如何帮助她。
One afternoon. Theresa was catching up with a group of friends.
[AI] 一天下午。特里萨正在和一群朋友聊天。
and one of them said.
[AI] 其中一个说。
"Theresa. how are you?"
[AI] “特里萨，你好吗？”
And she burst into tears.
[AI] 她哭了起来。
After she shared her story. one of her friends said.
[AI] 在她分享她的故事之后。她的一个朋友说。
"I went through the exact same thing with my son about a year ago."
[AI] “大约一年前，我和儿子经历了完全相同的事情。”
And in that moment.
[AI] 就在那一刻。
Theresa realized that so much of her struggle
[AI] 特蕾莎意识到她的很多挣扎
was not having anybody to talk with about it.
[AI] 没有人可以谈论这件事。
So she created a support group for parents like her.
[AI] 所以她为像她这样的父母建立了一个支持小组。
The first meeting was her and two other people.
[AI] 第一次见面是她和另外两个人。
But word spread. and soon 20 people. 30 people
[AI] 但是消息传开了。很快就有20个人。30人
were showing up for these monthly meetings that she put together.
[AI] 我们参加了她组织的月度会议。
She went from feeling helpless
[AI] 她不再感到无助
to realizing how capable she was of supporting her daughter.
[AI] 认识到她有能力养活女儿。
with the support of other people who were going through the same struggle.
[AI] 在经历同样斗争的其他人的支持下。
And Brianna is doing fantastic -- she's doing great academically and socially.
[AI] Brianna做得很好——她在学术和社交方面都做得很好。
That in the middle is my man Baakir.
[AI] 中间是我的男人Baakir。
standing in front of BlackStar Books and Caffe.
[AI] 站在黑星图书和咖啡馆前。
which he runs out of part of his house.
[AI] 他从房子的一部分跑出来。
As you walk in the door.
[AI] 当你走进门的时候。
Baakir greets you with a "Welcome black home."
[AI] 巴基尔用“欢迎黑人回家”来问候你
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
Once inside. you can order some Algiers jerk chicken.
[AI] 一进去。你可以点一些阿尔及尔鸡干。
perhaps a vegan walnut burger.
[AI] 也许是纯素核桃汉堡。
or jive turkey sammich.
[AI] 或者摇摆火鸡。
And that's sammich -- not sandwich.
[AI] 那是桑米奇，不是三明治。
You must finish your meal with a buttermilk drop.
[AI] 你必须在饭后滴一滴酪乳。
which is several steps above a donut hole
[AI] 在甜甜圈孔上方几步
and made from a very secret family recipe.
[AI] 由一个非常秘密的家庭食谱制成。
For real. it's very secret. he won't tell you about it.
[AI] 来真的这是非常秘密的。他不会告诉你的。
But BlackStar is much more than a café.
[AI] 但黑星不仅仅是一家咖啡馆。
For the kids in the neighborhood.
[AI] 给附近的孩子们。
it's a place to go after school to get help with homework.
[AI] 这是一个放学后去帮助做家庭作业的地方。
For the grown-ups. it's where they go
[AI] 对成年人来说。这就是他们要去的地方
to find out what's going on in the neighborhood
[AI] 看看附近发生了什么事
and catch up with friends.
[AI] 和朋友们见面。
It's a performance venue.
[AI] 这是一个表演场地。
It's a home for poets. musicians and artists.
[AI] 这是诗人的家。音乐家和艺术家。
Baakir and his partner Nicole.
[AI] 巴基尔和他的搭档妮可。
with their baby girl strapped to her back.
[AI] 背上绑着他们的女婴。
are there in the mix of it all.
[AI] 在这一切的混合中都有。
serving up a cup of coffee.
[AI] 端上一杯咖啡。
teaching a child how to play Mancala.
[AI] 教孩子如何玩曼卡拉。
or painting a sign for an upcoming community event.
[AI] 或者为即将到来的社区活动画一个标志。
I have worked with and learned from people just like them
[AI] 我和他们一样的人一起工作，一起学习
for more than 20 years.
[AI] 20多年了。
I have organized against the prison system.
[AI] 我组织起来反对监狱系统。
which impacts poor folks.
[AI] 这会影响穷人。
especially black. indigenous and Latino folks. at an alarming rate.
[AI] 尤其是黑色的。土著和拉丁美洲人。以惊人的速度。
I have worked with young people who manifest hope and promise.
[AI] 我曾与表现出希望和承诺的年轻人一起工作。
despite being at the effect of racist discipline practices in their schools.
[AI] 尽管受到学校种族主义纪律行为的影响。
and police violence in their communities.
[AI] 以及他们社区中的警察暴力。
I have learned from families
[AI] 我向家人学习
who are unleashing their ingenuity and tenacity
[AI] 他们正在发挥他们的聪明才智和毅力
to collectively create their own solutions.
[AI] 共同创造自己的解决方案。
And they're not just focused on money.
[AI] 他们不仅仅关注金钱。
They're addressing education. housing. health. community --
[AI] 他们正在解决教育问题。住房健康社区--
the things that we all care about.
[AI] 我们都关心的事情。
Everywhere I go.
[AI] 无论我去哪里。
I see people who are broke but not broken.
[AI] 我看到有人破产了，但没有破产。
I see people who are struggling to realize their good ideas.
[AI] 我看到人们正在努力实现他们的好想法。
so that they can create a better life for themselves.
[AI] 这样他们就能为自己创造更好的生活。
their families. their communities.
[AI] 他们的家人。他们的社区。
Jobana. Sintia. Bertha. Theresa and Baakir are the rule.
[AI] 乔巴纳。辛提亚。伯莎。特蕾莎和巴基尔是规则。
not the shiny exception.
[AI] 而不是闪亮的例外。
I am the exception.
[AI] 我是个例外。
I was raised by a quietly fierce single mother in Rochester. New York.
[AI] 我在罗切斯特由一位安静而凶猛的单身母亲抚养长大。纽约
I was bussed to a school in the suburbs. from a neighborhood
[AI] 我坐公共汽车去郊区的一所学校。邻居
that many of my classmates and their parents considered dangerous.
[AI] 我的很多同学和他们的父母都认为这很危险。
At eight. I was a latchkey kid.
[AI] 八点。我是一个带钥匙的孩子。
I'd get myself home after school every day and do homework and chores.
[AI] 我每天放学后回家做家庭作业和家务。
and wait for my mother to come home.
[AI] 等我妈妈回来。
After school. I'd go to the corner store
[AI] 放学后。我会去街角的商店
and buy a can of Chef Boyardee ravioli.
[AI] 买一罐厨师波亚迪饺子。
which I'd heat up on the stove as my afternoon snack.
[AI] 我会在炉子上加热，作为下午的点心。
If I had a little extra money. I'd buy a Hostess Fruit Pie.
[AI] 如果我有一点额外的钱。我想买一个女主人水果派。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
Cherry.
[AI] 樱桃
Not as good as a buttermilk drop.
[AI] 不如一滴酪乳好。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
We were poor when I was a kid.
[AI] 我小时候我们很穷。
But now. I own a home in a quickly gentrifying neighborhood in Oakland. California.
[AI] 但是现在。我在奥克兰一个迅速上流社会的社区里拥有一所房子。加利福尼亚
I've built a career.
[AI] 我已经建立了自己的事业。
My husband is a business owner.
[AI] 我丈夫是一个企业主。
I have a retirement account.
[AI] 我有一个退休帐户。
My daughter is not even allowed to turn on the stove
[AI] 我女儿甚至不准打开炉子
unless there's a grown-up at home
[AI] 除非家里有个大人
and she doesn't have to.
[AI] 她也不必这么做。
because she does not have to have the same kind of self-reliance that I had to at her age.
[AI] 因为她不必像我在她这个年龄时那样自力更生。
My kids' raviolis are organic
[AI] 我孩子吃的饺子是有机的
and full of things like spinach and ricotta.
[AI] 还有很多东西，比如菠菜和意大利乳清干酪。
because I have the luxury of choice
[AI] 因为我有很多选择
when it comes to what my children eat.
[AI] 说到我的孩子们吃什么。
I am the exception.
[AI] 我是个例外。
not because I'm more talented than Baakir
[AI] 不是因为我比巴基尔更有天赋
or my mother worked any harder than Jobana. Sintia or Bertha.
[AI] 或者我母亲比乔巴娜工作更努力。辛提亚或伯莎。
or cared any more than Theresa.
[AI] 或者比特蕾莎更关心她。
Marginalized communities are full of smart. talented people.
[AI] 边缘化社区充满了智慧。人才。
hustling and working and innovating.
[AI] 奔波、工作、创新。
just like our most revered and most rewarded CEOs.
[AI] 就像我们最受尊敬、回报最高的首席执行官一样。
They are full of people tapping into their resilience
[AI] 他们都是利用他们的韧性的人
to get up every day. get the kids off to school
[AI] 每天起床。让孩子们上学去
and go to jobs that don't pay enough.
[AI] 去做薪水不够的工作。
or get educations that are putting them in debt.
[AI] 或者接受让他们负债累累的教育。
They are full of people applying their savvy intelligence
[AI] 他们都是运用聪明才智的人
to stretch a minimum wage paycheck.
[AI] 延长最低工资。
or balance a job and a side hustle to make ends meet.
[AI] 或者平衡一份工作和一份兼职来维持收支平衡。
They are full of people doing for themselves and for others.
[AI] 他们都是为自己和他人做事的人。
whether it's picking up medication for an elderly neighbor.
[AI] 不管是为一个年老的邻居买药。
or letting a sibling borrow some money to pay the phone bill.
[AI] 或者让兄弟姐妹借点钱来付电话费。
or just watching out for the neighborhood kids from the front stoop.
[AI] 或者只是在门廊上照看附近的孩子。
I am the exception because of luck and privilege.
[AI] 因为幸运和特权，我是个例外。
not hard work.
[AI] 不是辛苦的工作。
And I'm not being modest or self-deprecating --
[AI] 我不是谦虚或自嘲--
I am amazing.
[AI] 我太棒了。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
But most people work hard.
[AI] 但是大多数人工作很努力。
Hard work is the common denominator in this equation.
[AI] 努力工作是这个等式的共同点。
and I'm tired of the story we tell
[AI] 我厌倦了我们讲的故事
that hard work leads to success.
[AI] 努力工作会带来成功。
because that allows --
[AI] 因为这允许--
Thank you.
[AI] 非常感谢。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）
... because that story allows those of us who make it to believe we deserve it.
[AI] ... 因为这个故事让我们这些成功的人相信我们值得拥有它。
and by implication.
[AI] 言下之意。
those who don't make it don't deserve it.
[AI] 那些做不到的人不值得。
We tell ourselves. in the back of our minds.
[AI] 我们告诉自己。在我们的脑海里。
and sometimes in the front of our mouths.
[AI] 有时在我们面前。
"There must be something a little wrong with those poor people."
[AI] “那些穷人一定有点不对劲。”
We have a wide range of beliefs about what that something wrong is.
[AI] 我们对什么是错误有着广泛的信念。
Some people tell the story that poor folks are lazy freeloaders
[AI] 有些人说穷人是懒惰的免费者
who would cheat and lie to get out of an honest day's work.
[AI] 谁会为了逃避一天诚实的工作而欺骗和撒谎。
Others prefer the story that poor people are helpless
[AI] 其他人更喜欢穷人无助的故事
and probably had neglectful parents that didn't read to them enough.
[AI] 可能有疏忽大意的父母没有给他们读足够的书。
and if they were just told what to do
[AI] 如果他们被告知该怎么办
and shown the right path.
[AI] 并显示了正确的路径。
they could make it.
[AI] 他们可以做到。
For every story I hear demonizing low-income single mothers
[AI] 我听到的每个故事都在妖魔化低收入单身母亲
or absentee fathers.
[AI] 或者缺席的父亲。
which is how people might think of my parents.
[AI] 这就是人们对我父母的看法。
I've got 50 that tell a different story about the same people.
[AI] 我有50本书讲述了同一个人的不同故事。
showing up every day and doing their best.
[AI] 每天都会出现，尽最大努力。
I'm not saying that some of the negative stories aren't true.
[AI] 我并不是说有些负面报道是不真实的。
but those stories allow us to not really see who people really are.
[AI] 但这些故事让我们无法真正了解人们到底是谁。
because they don't paint a full picture.
[AI] 因为他们没有描绘一幅完整的画面。
The quarter-truths and limited plot lines have us convinced
[AI] 四分之一的事实和有限的情节让我们信服
that poor people are a problem that needs fixing.
[AI] 穷人是一个需要解决的问题。
What if we recognized that what's working is the people
[AI] 如果我们认识到人民在起作用呢
and what's broken is our approach?
[AI] 我们的方法被打破了？
What if we realized that the experts we are looking for.
[AI] 如果我们意识到我们要找的专家。
the experts we need to follow.
[AI] 我们需要跟随的专家。
are poor people themselves?
[AI] 穷人本身就是穷人吗？
What if. instead of imposing solutions.
[AI] 如果…怎么办。而不是强加解决方案。
we just added fire to the already-burning flame that they have?
[AI] 我们只是在他们已经燃烧的火焰上添了火？
Not directing --
[AI] 不导演--
not even empowering --
[AI] 甚至没有授权--
but just fueling their initiative.
[AI] 但这仅仅是为了激发他们的主动性。
Just north of here.
[AI] 就在这里的北面。
we have an example of what this could look like:
[AI] 我们有一个这样的例子：
Silicon Valley.
[AI] 硅谷。
A whole venture capital industry has grown up around the belief
[AI] 整个风险投资行业都是围绕着这个信念成长起来的
that if people have good ideas and the desire to manifest them.
[AI] 如果人们有好的想法，并渴望实现它们。
we should give them lots and lots and lots of money.
[AI] 我们应该给他们很多很多很多很多的钱。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
Right? But where is our strategy for Theresa and Baakir?
[AI] 正当但我们对特蕾莎和巴基尔的策略在哪里？
There are no incubators for them.
[AI] 他们没有孵化器。
no accelerators. no fellowships.
[AI] 没有加速器。没有奖学金。
How are Jobana. Sintia and Bertha really all that different
[AI] 乔巴纳怎么样。辛蒂亚和伯莎真的很不一样
from the Mark Zuckerbergs of the world?
[AI] 来自世界的马克·扎克伯格？
Baakir has experience and a track record.
[AI] Baakir拥有丰富的经验和良好的业绩记录。
I'd put my money on him.
[AI] 我会把钱押在他身上。
So. consider this an invitation to rethink a flawed strategy.
[AI] 所以认为这是一个重新考虑有缺陷的战略的邀请。
Let's grasp this opportunity
[AI] 让我们抓住这个机会
to let go of a tired. faulty narrative
[AI] 放下一个疲惫的。错误的叙述
and listen and look for true stories.
[AI] 倾听并寻找真实的故事。
more beautifully complex stories.
[AI] 更美丽复杂的故事。
about who marginalized people and families and communities are.
[AI] 关于被边缘化的人、家庭和社区是谁。
I'm going to take a minute to speak to my people.
[AI] 我要花一分钟和我的人谈谈。
We cannot wait
[AI] 我们不能等待
for somebody else to get it right.
[AI] 让别人做对。
Let us remember what we are capable of;
[AI] 让我们记住我们的能力；
all that we have built with blood. sweat and dreams;
[AI] 我们用鲜血建造的一切。汗水与梦想；
all the cogs that keep turning;
[AI] 所有不断转动的齿轮；
and the people kept afloat because of our backbreaking work.
[AI] 由于我们的艰苦工作，人民得以生存。
Let us remember that we are magic.
[AI] 让我们记住我们是魔法。
If you need some inspiration to jog your memory.
[AI] 如果你需要一些灵感来唤起你的记忆。
read Octavia Butler's "Parable of the Sower."
[AI] 阅读奥克塔维亚·巴特勒的《播种者的寓言》
Listen to Reverend King's "Letter from Birmingham Jail."
[AI] 听一下金牧师的“伯明翰监狱的信”
Listen to Suheir Hammad recite "First Writing Since."
[AI] 听Suheir Hammad背诵“自那时以来的第一篇写作”
or Esperanza Spalding perform "Black Gold."
[AI] 或者埃斯佩兰萨·斯伯丁表演“黑金”
Set your gaze upon the art of Kehinde Wiley or Favianna Rodriguez.
[AI] 把你的目光放在凯欣德·威利或法维亚娜·罗德里格斯的艺术上。
Look at the hands of your grandmother
[AI] 看看你祖母的手
or into the eyes of someone who loves you.
[AI] 或者在爱你的人眼里。
We are magic.
[AI] 我们是魔法。
Individually. we don't have a lot of wealth and power.
[AI] 个别地。我们没有很多财富和权力。
but collectively. we are unstoppable.
[AI] 但总体而言。我们势不可挡。
And we spend a lot of our time and energy
[AI] 我们花了很多时间和精力
organizing our power to demand change from systems that were not made for us.
[AI] 组织我们的力量，要求改变不是为我们设计的系统。
Instead of trying to alter the fabric of existing ways.
[AI] 而不是试图改变现有方式的结构。
let's weave and cut some fierce new cloth.
[AI] 让我们织一些新布，剪一些新布。
Let's use some of our substantial collective power
[AI] 让我们利用我们的一些强大的集体力量
toward inventing and bringing to life
[AI] 朝着发明和赋予生命的方向
new ways of being that work for us.
[AI] 对我们有用的新生活方式。
Desmond Tutu talks about the concept of ubuntu.
[AI] 德斯蒙德·图图谈到了ubuntu的概念。
in the context of South Africa's Truth and Reconciliation process
[AI] 在南非真相与和解进程的背景下
that they embarked on after apartheid.
[AI] 他们在种族隔离后开始的。
He says it means.
[AI] 他说这意味着。
"My humanity is caught up. is inextricably bound up. in yours;
[AI] “我的人性被抓住了。与你的人性紧密相连；
we belong to a bundle of life."
[AI] 我们属于一群生命。"
A bundle of life.
[AI] 一束生命。
The Truth and Reconciliation process
[AI] 真相与和解进程
started by elevating the voices of the unheard.
[AI] 首先是提高那些闻所未闻的人的声音。
If this country is going to live up to its promise of liberty and justice for all.
[AI] 如果这个国家要实现它对所有人的自由和正义的承诺。
then we need to elevate the voices of our unheard.
[AI] 然后，我们需要提高我们闻所未闻的声音。
of people like Jobana. Sintia and Bertha.
[AI] 像Jobana这样的人。辛提亚和伯莎。
Theresa and Baakir.
[AI] 特里萨和巴基尔。
We must leverage their solutions and their ideas.
[AI] 我们必须利用他们的解决方案和想法。
We must listen to their true stories.
[AI] 我们必须倾听他们的真实故事。
their more beautifully complex stories.
[AI] 他们更美丽复杂的故事。
Thank you.
[AI] 非常感谢。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）